# MORGAN GASS SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

7632 Bondesson Street Omaha, NE 68122 morgan.gass@gmail.com www.morgangass.net 605-661-6569

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Software developer with seven years of experience developing, testing, and enhancing new and existing applications. Hard-working and enthusiastic about learning new languages and technologies. Self-motivated, passionate, and in search of new and interesting challenges to enhance and acquire skills.

#### TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- 7 years software development experience using various tools, technologies, and languages.
- 4 years of object-oriented software development in C# and Java.
- Self-directed in skill improvement.
- Skilled at managing multiple projects simultaneously and meeting assigned deadlines.
- Proficient at debugging and troubleshooting legacy applications.

Languages: C#/ASP.NET, Java, JavaScript, C++, Perl, PHP, Python, SQL, TypeScript, VBA

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server 2005/2008/2012, Oracle SQL, MySQL

Microsoft Frameworks/Technologies: .NET 2.0-4.6, LINQ, Web API, ASP.NET, Entity Framework

**Open Standards/Open Source based Technologies:** Angular, AngularJS, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, Jasmine, jQuery, JSON, SOAP, XML

**IDEs:** Android Studio, Eclipse, Microsoft Visual Studio 2010-2015, Oracle SQL Developer, SQL Server Management Studio 2008-2012, Visual Studio Code

Source Control and Build Tools: Git, MSBuild, Octopus Deploy, Team Foundation Server

**Development Methodologies:** Agile and Waterfall development methodologies, MVC frameworks, Unit Testing

Hosting Technologies and Platforms: Apache, IBM P8 FileNet, IIS 7/8, Linux, Windows Server 2008/2012

Other Technologies: Android

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, DTN

Omaha, NE June 2016 – present

- Utilized agile methodologies and test-driven development techniques.
- Built and maintained web-based, internally-developed business applications using ASP.NET.
- Work independent of day to day supervision to achieve all goals and objectives.
- Identify opportunities to improve current processes and procedures.
- Collaborated with Quality Assurance team to ensure adequate test coverage.
- Oversaw customization and maintenance of application deployment tool.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

## Business Systems Analyst, ConAgra Foods, Inc.

Omaha, NE

September 2012 – May 2016

- Automated complex business and IT processes using various programming languages, tools, and technologies.
- Automated metrics aggregation and reporting for legacy workflow system using Java and Microsoft MVC framework.
- Supported, enhanced, and decommissioned software applications as necessitated by business changes.
- Collaborated with the business to gather requirements for and develop applications to facilitate system inter-connectivity and reporting.
- Built and maintained web-based, internally-developed business applications using ASP.NET and Java.
- Mentored and trained interns and new developers on TFS source control best practices.
- Managed initiative to modernize internal web hosting infrastructure and monitoring strategy using ASP.NET and TFS.
- Implemented custom Web API replacement for legacy Java application portfolio management system.

## Associate IT Analyst, ConAgra Foods, Inc.

Omaha, NE

May 2012 – September 2012

- Assisted customers in diagnosing and troubleshooting system and application issues.
- Designed and implemented internally hosted wiki for entire Help Desk organization to serve as a centralized repository for documentation.
- Implemented a set of tools and reports in PHP used to monitor the health and status of the Help Desk wiki.

### Information Technology Intern, ConAgra Foods, Inc.

Omaha, NE

January 2010 - May 2012

- Rotated through four separate teams within the IT department to achieve broader understating of IT and business processes.
- Provided direct support to users within IT organization and business customers.
- Enhanced existing reporting procedures with automated processes using VBA.
- Developed reporting and data aggregation applications.
- Transitioned to full-time position upon successful completion of intern program.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Master of Science in Computer Science**

University of Nebraska at Omaha – Omaha, NE Fall 2011 – Winter 2012

GPA: 3.94 / 4.00

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** 

University of Nebraska at Omaha – Omaha, NE

GPA: 3.79 / 4.00

Fall 2007 – Spring 2011

# REFERENCES

Available upon request.